NICO MELE

User Experience Designer

My name is Nico, I am a User Esperience Designer and creative problem solver based in Sydney. After working as a marketing professional for 7 years, I recently transitioned to the world of UX to satisfy my thirst for creativity and combine it with existing skillsets. I am passionate about creating digital experiences that get to the core of the problem and put the users' needs at the centre of the design process. I'd love to tell you more about what gets me excited, let's grab a coffee (or a slice of pizza without pineapple).

CONTACT



Sydney, AU



nicomele1@gmail.com



0421718949



nicoapples.com



linkedin.com/in/nicomele/



@nicoapples

TOOLS

Sketch | Invision | Axure Pen & Paper | Balsamiq Marvel | Keynote Adobe Creative Cloud Google Analytics | Trello

UX SKILLS

UI Prototyping | Sketching Rapid Wireframing Iterative Design Personas | Storyboarding Affinity Mapping Usability Testing Information Architecture Interviews & Surveys Data Analysis

INTERESTS

Cats | Photography | Travels Netflix | E-commerce | Cycling Pizza (without pineapple) | Movies

EDUCATION

General Assembly Sydney | 2017 User Experience Design Immersive

University of Sydney | 2011 Masters of Media Practice (Merit)

University of Sydney | 2009 Masters of Publishing (Merit)

IULM University, Milan | 2007 BA of Communication (Honours)

WORK HISTORY

UX CONSULTANT

NSW State Emergency Service | Jan 2018 - Feb 2018

NSW SES is an emergency and rescue service dedicated to assisting the community with over 9,000 volunteers across the state. As a UX consultant, I worked on the design of a mobile app that would allow for volunteers to enter their availability and SES management to allocate volunteers to emergency jobs. Throughout the project I conducted early research, developed an interactive prototype that was the results of three design iterations and conducted usability testing. The final designs were developed and presented to the NSW SES Commissioner in February 2018.

CO-FOUNDER | EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Cool As A Fox | July 2015 - Present

I am the proud owner of Cool As A Fox, an e-commerce selling colourful, gender-neutral socks. I started the business with my partner as an outlet to express my creativity and in just two years it has grown from a small side project to a successful e-commerce with over 4000 happy customers in Australia. My focus is on delivering a seemless experience to our customers, from when they first visit the website to the moment they receive their socks delivery. I am in charge of website design, marketing, collaborations with local designers, liaising with the manufacturers and logistics.

PROJECT MANAGER | DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST

ITS Management | Sept 2011 - Sept 2017

ITSM is a digital marketing agency. During my six-years stint at ITS Management I started my role developing and implementing email marketing campaigns, I was then promoted to Project Manager and was in charge of managing large scale digital projects from start to finish. Over the years I have done extensive data analysis, user research, usability testing, stakeholder management and worked closely with devs and designers to bring ideas to life.

EDITORIAL ASSISTANT

Edge Custom Media | 2009

Edge Custom Media is a publishing house specialised in custom publishing solutions. I worked on several publications and my tasks included writing short features, copy-editing, proofreading, image and background research.

ACCOUNT COORDINATOR

K.Media | 2006 - 2007

K.Media is an independent media representative based in Milan. My duties included helping develop and monitoring advertising campaigns for clients including the Telegraph Group and writing media releases.